Guide to the Amos Alonzo Stagg Papers 1866-1964
University of Chicago Library
- Series VIII: Scrapbooks, Notebooks, and Albums
  - Subseries 5: Amos Alonzo Stagg Football Notebooks
    - Football Notebook No. 46, Football Plays 1942 Season, II - Includes notes on practices, pre-game and practice to do lists, rosters, notes and commentary on College of the Pacific games, diagrams of plays, offense and defense notes, letters, strategies, and averages of passes and yards run. (Box 288)
    - Football Notebook No. 47, Football Plays, A.A, Stagg, Jr. 1935-42 (Folders 1,2, 3) - Contains letters to A.A. Stagg and Stella R. Stagg and Paul Stagg, Susquehanna University football, plays with diagrams and notes, descriptions of games, plays and formations, advice and questions, and statistics on Susquehanna football. (Box 289)
    - Football Notebook No. 48, Football Plays 1943 Season, I (Folder I) - Includes defense plays and strategies for the College of the Pacific, squad and roster lists, reports on practices, techniques for offense and blocking systems, diagrams of systems and plays, and pre-game notes and preparations. (Box 289)
    - Football Notebook No. 49, Football Plays 1943, II (Folder 1,2, 3) - College of the Pacific plays and formations with diagrams, reports and notes on practices and games, strategies, defense systems, lists of plays and passes, rosters and squad lists, details and accounts from the movie of College of the Pacific vs. the Coast Guard. Also includes miscellaneous notes for plays and practices, and athletic letters and awards to be given out. (Box 289)
    - Football Notebook No. 50, Football Plays 1944 Season, I - The notebook has letters to Stagg sons regarding football, notes for the season, notes on practices and games, diagrams of plays, coaching tips, techniques for plays and punts. Also contains strategies for blocking and passing, player and candidate lists, eligibility lists, new offense systems and principles, and lists of used, received and incomplete passes. (Box 290)
    - Football Notebook No. 51, Football Plays 1944 Season, II - Contains lists of forward passes used during the season, plays and formations with diagrams, notes and reports on practices and games, eligibility lists, rosters, game averages, pre-game to do lists, scrimmages, and defenses used against the College of the Pacific. (Box 290)
    - Football Notebook No. 52, Football Plays 1944 Season, III (Folders 1 and 2) - Includes rosters, eligibility and squad lists for the College of the Pacific, diagrams of plays, notes and reports on practices and games, football nomenclature, notes and lists of plays, formations and passes. Also contains game notices, defense and offense strategies, to do lists, instruction for football managers, award recommendations, and statistics broken down by player per game. (Box 290)
    - Football Notebook No. 53, Football Plays 1945 - Includes College of the Pacific football receipts, diagrams of plays, team notices, offense and defense strategies, candidate lists, rosters, eligibility lists, notes and analysis of practices, letters to family regarding games and plays, lists of yells and cheers, and strategies for games. (Box 291)
    - Football Notebook No. 54, Football Plays 1946 Season, I (Folders 1 and 2) - College of the Pacific football nomenclature for signals, explanations of formations, diagrams and drawings of plays, notes on spring practice, reports on games and practices, lists of candidates, lists of passes used, strategies, and to do lists. (Box 291)
    - Football Notebook No. 55, Football Plays 1946 Season, II - Contains College of the Pacific game and practice notes and suggestions, drawings and diagrams, team notices, defense and offense suggestions and strategies, rosters of opposing teams, signals, and notes on passing. (Box 291)
    - Football Notebook No. 56, Football Plays 1947 Season, I - Susquehanna University football schedules, to do lists, Susquehanna nomenclature for games and practices, passing systems, plays with diagrams, offense and defense directions, formations, and notes on coaching techniques. (Box 292)
    - Football Notebook No. 57, Football Plays 1947 Season, II (Folders 1 and 2) - Includes Susquehanna University season plays, formations, passes and punts, diagrams and notations, and systems of plays with nomenclature. Also has lists with descriptions and explanations, notes and strategies for practices and games, problems, observations, scrimmages, defense and offense notes, to do lists, and lists of passes, punts and running plays. (Box 292)
    - Football Notebook No. 58, Football Plays 1948 Season, I (Folders 1 and 2) - Contains Susquehanna football schedules, notes on plays, games, and practices, letters to Stagg family with regard to plays, passes, and formations, analysis of the season, commentary on defense and offense, and pre-game notes and suggestions. (Box 292)
    - Football Notebook No. 59, Football Plays 1948 Season, II (Folders 1 and 2) - Includes Susquehanna passing plays, diagrams, pre-game and practice to do lists commentary on practices, game strategies, signals, pointers, and plays and formations. (Box 293)
    - Football Notebook No. 60, Football Plays 1949 Season, Workbook I - (Folders 1 and 2) - Contains lists of players and their positions, defense and offense strategies, nomenclature on passes, offense systems, diagrams of plays and formations, Susquehanna football schedules, coaching pointers, notes, and to do lists. (Box 293)
    - Football Notebook No. 61, Football Plays 1949 Season, Workbook II - (Folders 1 and 2) - This notebook has drawings and diagrams of plays, formations, offense strategies, and a letter from Stagg, Jr. about changes in team positions. (Box 293)
    - Football Notebook No. 62, Football Plays 1949 Season, Final Workbook III - (Folders 1 and 2) - Susquehanna University football formations and plays with descriptions and diagrams, lists of passes and runs used, lists of players and positions, offense strategies, notes and reports on games and practices, and mistakes made during games. (Box 293)
    - Football Notebook No. 63, Football Plays 1950 Season - Includes Susquehanna plays and diagrams, squad lists, notes on plays and strategies for plays, and a football schedule. (Box 294)
    - Football Notebook No. 64, Unidentified Football Plays (Possibly Chicago) (Folder 1) - Contains only drawings and diagrams of Plays and formations. (Box 294)
    - Football Notebook No. 65, Mckeever’s Lectures, Oklahoma Coaching School, 1946 (Folder 1) - Lectures on formations and developing signal systems, line blocking, teaching coaching, how to work with and develop linemen and blocking, diagrams, ways to use different plays and why they are useful, offensive guard plays, passing and punting, the importance of scouting and defensive planning. (Box 294)
    - Football Notebook No. 66, Fritz Crisler’s Football Lectures, 1946 (Folder 1) - From the Oklahoma Coaching School, and includes Coach Carl Snavely’s single wing back formation with diagrams and corresponding notes and commentary. Also contains Fritz Crisler’s signal system for defense, breakdowns of plays, offense strategies, defense playas and counter defenses, diagrams, components of blocking and tackling, creating an opening in defense, fumbling, punting and protection for the “kicking game.” (Box 294)
  - Subseries 6: Duplicate Football Notebooks
    - Duplicate Football Notebooks No. 1, Fall Football Workbook 1934 (Folders 1 and 2) - Includes reports on scrimmages, games and practices. These reports include kicking and passing contests, injuries, freshmen practices, successes, techniques used, plays, strategies and defenses. The notebook also contains commentary and observations on games and practices, lists of plays used, assessments of the College of the Pacific team, defense strategies, criticisms of plays and strategies, and scouted games. (Box 295)
    - Duplicate Football Notebooks No. 2, Fall and Spring Football 1935 (Folders 1 and 2) - College of the Pacific spring practice notes and reports for 1935 are contained in this notebook, in addition to passes, new techniques for punting, blocking and tackling, attendance records, running contests, scrimmages and football records. Also included are coaching observations and assessments for 1935 season and team, lists of plays and signals, tackling averages, lists of player weaknesses, and rosters and commentary on football candidates. (Box 295)
    - Duplicate Football Notebooks No. 3, Spring Practice Workbook 1935 (Folders 1, 2, 3 and 1 Oversize) (see Box 338 for oversized items) - Contains rosters of football candidates, squad divisions for scrimmages, scouting notes, lists of candidates who qualify for games, conditions for spring football practice, notes on scrimmages, and suggestions for practices. The notebook also has attendance records for practices, letters to players regarding pre-season conditioning and encouragement, strategies, development of punting, kicking, blocking, and passing techniques, plays and diagrams, assessments of team practices and problems, notices to teams and reports on practices. Also includes tackling and passing summaries, time trials, signals, and lists of candidates with skills assessments and problems. (Box 295)
    - Duplicate Football Notebooks No. 4, Football Workbook 1935 (Folders 1 and 2) - This notebook contains retrospectives of College of the Pacific football season of 1935 and includes team morale, financial and college administrative problems, the use of reserves, and a breakdown of each game for the 1935 season. It also has defense notes, scoring plays, lists of points scored in each game by team and player, touchdown plays and passes, diagrams, reports on games, rosters, strategies, observations, weight of each varsity player, and lists of the amount of time played by individual team member. (Box 295)
    - Duplicate Football Notebooks No. 5, Spring Football 1936 (Folders 1 and 2) - Includes attendance records, notes on practices, injury reports, to-do lists for practices, plays with diagrams, team assessments, reports on practices, season evaluations, strategies, scrimmages, summary of passes, and letters to Paul Stagg regarding coaching, plays, and observations on College of the Pacific practices. (Box 295)
    - Duplicate Football Notebooks No. 6, Spring Football 1936 (Folders 1 and 2) - Contains coaching goals and decisions for the 1936 season, attendance records, injury reports, notes on the spring season, scrimmages, to-do lists and suggestions. Also has a list of player weight, reports and evaluations on practices, diagrams and plays, lists of passes, strategies, and letters to Paul Stagg regarding College of the Pacific football practices, team assessments, and plays. (Box 296)
    - Duplicate Football Notebooks No. 7, Fall Football 1936 (Folders 1 and 2) - This notebook contains rosters and squad lists of possible varsity candidates for College of the Pacific football, game schedules, letters to Paul Stagg with plays, offensive strategies and overall game strategies, notes for the 1936 season, coaching goals and issues, and reports on practices. It also has reports on scrimmages, nomenclature lists, passes used, defense notes, signals, formations, and anecdotes and notes on conversations and stories regarding College of the Pacific football. (Box 296)
    - Duplicate Football Notebooks No. 8, Spring Football 1937 (also Items) (Folders 1,2, 3) - Includes letters regarding College of the Pacific football and officials for games, season prospects for 1937, a breakdown of high schools with players now on the freshman squad, rosters, and the resumes of the College of the Pacific football coaches. This notebook also contains a statistical history of Stagg’s coaching at the College of the Pacific, schedules, analysis of positions with valuable or promising players, strategies, rosters for Salinas Junior College, Stockton Junior College and University of California at Davis football, “P” varsity letter certificates, and lists of game officials. Also has scholastic records and standings of College of Pacific football team, reports on practices, list of the 1937 team’s summer employment, diagrams, lists of signals, scrimmages, to-do lists, individual player weight, assessments for the 1936 and 1937 season, and forms letters to varsity players from Stagg. (Box 296)
    - Duplicate Football Notebooks No. 9, Spring Football 1937 (Folders 1 and 2) - College of the Pacific football practice notes and reports are contained here, in addition to passing techniques, coaching needs and goals, lists of signals, scrimmages, plays and diagrams, passing developments, commentary on the freshman squad, football nomenclature, strategy, to-do lists, and game notes, reports and commentary. (Box 296)
  - Subseries 7: Scouting and University of Chicago Athletics Notebooks
    - Scouting Notebooks No. 1, 1920-1921 (Folder 1) - Scouted plays and formations used for South Dakota, Iowa, Illinois, and Wisconsin. (Box 297)
    - Scouting Notebooks No. 2, 1926-1932 - Scouting reports on Big Ten football teams, Dartmouth and Vanderbilt. Also contains diagrams of plays and passes, coaching strategies, University of Illinois rosters, formations, and Fritz Crisler’s passes and offense system. (Box 297)
    - Scouting Notebooks No. 3, 1933-1934 (Folders 1 and 2) - Contains reports on Big Ten plays and diagrams, kicking game, scouting reports by A. A. Stagg, Jr., breakdowns of players, weight, skills, and positions, defense strategies, problems and successes. (Box 298)
    - Scouting Notebooks No. 4, 1937-1944 (Folders 1, 2, 3, 4 and 1 Oversize) - Includes drawings and diagrams of various other intercollegiate football team plays (Michigan State, University of Arizona, Gonzaga University, USC, Dartmouth, Stanford, Los Angeles State, Princeton, Army, Harvard, UCLA, Notre Dame, Cornell, and the University of Michigan). Also contains newspaper clippings with plays, breakdowns of the College of the Pacific games, notes on Harvard’s plays, Fritz Crisler’s plays, scouted plays by the Stagg family, letters, coaching needs, conditions and strengths, Mohlenburg’s Offense for 1944, and a section of the Chronicle Sporting Green. (see Box 338 for oversized items) (Box 298)
    - Baseball Notebook No. 1, 1893-1933 (Notebook and Additional Folder) - Covers practice games, schedules, roster lists, Order of the “C” winners, games played and scores, lists of “champions,” lists of captain with positions, Japan tour information, and lists of victories and defeats. (Box 299)
    - Baseball Notebook No. 2, Practice and Summer Games 1894-1928 (Folder 1) - Contains summer baseball schedules by season with the number of innings, and scheduled practice games with number of innings and divided by year. (Box 299)
    - Swimming Notebook No. 1, 1900-1932 (Folders 1 and 2) - Contains lists of Order of the “C” winners by year, water polo games with results, roster lists, relay teams, swimming records, try-out results, and best swimming performances. Also contains meet results with times and competitors, intercollegiate conference results, performance charts, NCAA meet results, swimming programs, and the results of the Interscholastic Swimming Meet, January 8, 1932. (Box 299)
    - Swimming Notebook No. 2, 1917-1933 (Notebook and Additional Folder) - Swimming ledger with lists of each swimmer by event and with results and times. Also includes dates of races and teams competing, University of Chicago yearly records, conference meet results, point tables for conference meets, the official summary of the Twenty-third Annual Swimming Championships Western Intercollegiate Conference Athletic Association, and time sheets for preliminary and final racing heats. (Box 299)
    - Basketball Notebook No. 1, 1893-1931 - Includes lists of the Order of the “C” winners from 1908-1931, rosters and schedules, games and results by year, and handwritten excerpts from newspapers about University of Chicago basketball and developing a varsity basketball team. (Box 300)
    - Basketball Notebook No. 2, Interscholastic Basketball 1917-1932 (Folder 1) - Contains dates and games of the Interscholastic Basketball tournaments played at the University of Chicago, lists of semifinalist high school from 1917-1922, tournament placement charts of the teams, and scores of the games. (Box 300)
    - Fencing Notebook No. 1, 1908-1933 - This notebook contains intercollegiate fencing schedules, lists of the Order of the “C” winners, includes excerpts from 1896-1898 newspapers concerning the organization of fencing at the University of Chicago and the formation of a fencing club. Also includes lists of fencing team members, meet results, amateur fencing league of America tournament results, conference meets, invitational meets, and conference standings. (Box 300)
    - Wrestling Notebook No.1, 1921-1932 (Folders 1 and 2) - Wrestling meets and results organized by team member, weight class and year, lists of team members per year, schedules, weight class events, Western Intercollegiate Conference tournaments and preliminary meets. Also contains results, charts with team standings, interscholastic wrestling 1926-1927, 1931-1932, wrestling awards, entry blank forms for 1926 first interscholastic wrestling meet, notes on meets, and invitational and championship meets with results. (Box 300)
    - Tennis Notebook No. 1, 1892-1933 - University of Chicago intercollegiate tennis tournaments and matches, winners of the “Order of the C,” lists of the first 1893 tennis club of Chicago, officers of the Tennis Association 1895-1898, spring championships and summer tournaments, fall, faculty, and students games, team standing charts, scores, and interscholastic tennis. (Box 301)
    - Tennis Notebook No. 2, 1894-1904, Tennis 1917-1925, Cross Country 1901-1904 - Contains lists of 1903-1904 tennis team members, tournaments, schedules, individual and doubles matches, team lists, scores, 1925 interscholastic tennis, cross country running members, try-outs, individual times, coaches, race routes, runners, races, and an account of the first Intercollegiate Cross Country Run under the auspices of the Intercollegiate Cross Country Association. Also has tables listing the 1894-1904 instruction of athletics per season by the Department of Physical Culture at the University of Chicago, Department of Physical Culture rules governing contracting games between universities, regulations for student and graduate student representatives on the athletic board, and rules for students participating in sports. (Box 301)
    - Tennis Notebook No. 3, Summer Tournaments 1900-1916 (Folder 1) - Includes lists of matches by date, singles and doubles tournaments, scores, and names of players. (Box 301)
    - Tennis Notebook No. 4, Tennis 1917-1933 (Notebook and Additional Folder) - Tournaments and results of University of Chicago tennis, individual and doubles matches, team scores, charts of team standings for conference tournaments, 1917-1932 interscholastic tournaments with charts of team standings and scores, and lists of University of Chicago team members. (Box 301)
    - Golf Notebook No. 1, 1898-1933 (Folders 1 and 2) - Contains lists of the Order of the “C” winners 1920-1928, handwritten excerpts from newspaper clippings covering the formation of a golf team at the University of Chicago, summer golf, tournaments, results of matches, lists of team members, and try-outs for games. Also covers individual championships, Western Intercollegiate Golf tournaments and conference meets, charts by year of tournaments, schedules, records of individual scores, and unofficial results of the Intercollegiate Conference Golf Tournament. (Box 302)
    - Gymnastics Notebook No. 1, 1895-1933 (1 Oversize) - Includes meet schedules and school standings, correspondence about team records, meet results, and the Intercollegiate Gymnastics Association, lists of the Order of the “C” winners, results by year of championships, and Western Intercollegiate Gymnastics meets of 1903 to 1920. Also has handwritten excerpts from newspaper clippings regarding the formation of a league of gymnasts, lists of team members, meet events with scores, team, individual and judges’ scores summaries of annual intercollegiate gymnastics meets, 1920 oversize championship meet program, and the rules governing gymnastics meets. (see Box 338 for oversized items) (Box 302)
    - Cross Country Running Notebook No. 1, (Folder 1) - Covers the Western Conference Cross Country Championships and meets by year, lists the winners of the “C” and captains of the cross country team by year, and names the top placing schools and individual winners with times of Western and Intercollegiate meets. Also contains records on the formation of the Cross Country Club at the University of Chicago, team members, try-out results, and records of the formation of the Western Intercollegiate Cross Country Association. Includes letters regarding the University of Chicago cross country team, records of the first Intercollegiate Cross Country Run, meet results, Central Amateur Athletics Union meet results, and lists of individual winners by finish. (Box 302)
    - Track Notebooks No. 1, Track and Field 1893-1906 (Notebook and Additional Folder) - Includes records of the 1894-1897 Western Intercollegiate Amateur Athletics Association for sprints, hurdles, distance, bicycling, jumping, and field events, notes on individual points, meets, scores for meets, place times, and records of the First Annual Field Day. Also contains records, participants, distance and times for track meets, scores of points, individual records, Intercollegiate Conference Athletic Association meets, freshman try-outs, interscholastic events, Olympic Intercollegiate Championships, and University of Chicago indoor and outdoor records. (Box 303)
    - Track Notebooks No. 2, Track and Field 1906-1910 - Contains lists of University of Chicago Order of the “C” winners, individual records of practices and meets, account of the First Regiment Armory, rosters of freshman and varsity teams, and schedules and scores by season. Also includes Pennsylvania relays, championships, freshmen and varsity meets, Interscholastic records, Olympic try-outs at Marshall Field, University of Chicago athletic records, and a birthday. (Box 303)
    - Track Notebooks No. 3, Track and Field 1910-1916 - University of Chicago track and field schedules are included, also freshmen rosters, meets with scores, conference meets, relays, interscholastic meets and records, University of Chicago seasonal records, lists of Order of the “C” winners, individual records and results, and championship meets of the Central Amateur Athletics Union. (Box 303)
    - Track Notebooks No. 4, Track and Field 1916-1923 - This notebook contains University of Chicago track and field meets and seasonal records, individual records, rosters, scores, finish results, relays and carnivals, Intercollegiate Conference meets, lists of individual points from meets, interscholastic games and records, and Amateur Athletic Union Championships. (Box 303)
    - Track Notebooks No. 5, Track and Field 1923-1930 (Notebook and Additional Folder) - Includes records for the First NCAA meet at Stagg Field including receipts and expenditures, prorating and expense reports for NCAA 1921-1932, schedules for all NCAA meets 1921-1944, and list of team champions of the NCAA 1921-1944. Also contains scores of teams for the National Collegiate Track and Field meets 1925-1927, grid listing schools with events and scores of meets, notes on counting of points, team championships, new NCAA records and data on NCAA championships, events, and results. (Box 304)